你知道再4个星期 我们就要结婚了吗？
Do you realize we're getting married in four weeks?
4个星期 宝贝 4个星期
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
你知道你每个星期都 越来越大声吗？
You realize you get louder each week?
还有这么多事要做  你写好你的婚礼誓词了吗？
There's still so much to do! Have you written your vows?
我想我会去买 "派特 我要买婚礼誓词"
I figured I'd just buy those. "Pat, I'd like to buy a vow." Ha, ha.
亲爱的 你知道讲到婚礼 我是没有幽默感的
You know I've no sense of humor when it comes to this.
- 对 你写了你的吗？ - 还没 但我知道我要说什么
- Right. Have you written yours yet?     - No, but I know what I'm gonna say.
你会不会刚好知道 我要讲什么？
Do you happen to know what I'm gonna say?
现在写 没有那么困难
Let's do it now. It won't be hard.
说你心里想的
Say what's in your heart.
看她写得多快 她一定爱我比我爱她多
Look at her go. She must love me more than I love her!
我有什么问题？ 噢 不要打开那扇门
What's wrong with me? Ooh, don't open that door.
"摩妮卡 没有字…"
Phew. "Monica, there are no words..."
没有字 这不应该这么难
There are no words! This shouldn't be this hard!
这你做过了 你的婚礼誓词里说什么？
Uh... Oh! You've done this before. What did you say in your vows?
对卡萝 我保证过 到死不会再爱别的女人
With Carol I promised never to love another woman until I die.
她没有这样保证过
She made no such promise.
我真悲哀 摩妮卡知道要讲什么 看她下笔如飞的样子
I'm pathetic. Monica knows what to say, you should have seen her.
摩妮卡 什么紧急大事？
What's the emergency?
帮我忙 我一定要写婚礼誓词 可是我只有这些
You have to help me write my vows. All I have is this.
嗯 我喜欢你穿婚纱的图画
I like the pretty drawing of you in the wedding dress.
- 谢谢   - 只除了你的胸部看来有点小
- Thank you.     - Except your breasts look small.
那是我的眼睛
Those are my eyes!
- 那才是我的胸部   - 是噢 好吧
- Those are my breasts.     - Oh, yeah.
你何不从简单的开始？
Why don't you start with something simple?
像是…
Like, um:
"摩妮卡 我第一次见到你 就知道我爱你"
"Monica, from the moment I met you I knew I loved you."
我不确定我能这么说
I can't do that.
各位 这是钱德
Everyone, this is Chandler.
我是罗斯的小妹
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
是噢
Okay.
好 也许你这么起头好了
Okay, okay. Um, maybe you could start with:
"钱德 即使在我们还是朋友时…
"Chandler, even though we were friends...
内心深处一直知道我想要更多"
...there was a part of me that knew I wanted more."
好吧 发生了一场核子浩劫 我是地球上最后一个男人
All right, there's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on Earth.
你会和我约会吗？
Would you go out with me?
婚礼誓词里可以说谎吗？
Ooh! Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
也许那时不要谈你的感情 就说些…
Okay, don't talk about those feelings. Just say something about...
他教会你的事 像是…
...all the things he's taught you, like...
或是你教会他的事
Or all the things you taught him.
大家都知道基本的性感带 有1 2 3…
Everybody knows the erogenous zones. One, two, three...
4 5 6 7
...four, five, six and seven.
有7个？
There are seven?
- 那算是一个吗？ - 蛮重要的
- That's one?     - Heh, heh. Kind of an important one.
我是倒着看的
I was looking at it upside down.
有时候这样也有帮助的
Ha. You know, sometimes that helps.
好 现在 由1开始…
Okay, start out with a little one...
2 1-2-3…
...a two, a one-two-three...
3 5…
...a three, a five...
4 3-2…
...a four, a three-two...
2 2-4-6
...two, a two-four-six.
2-4-6   4   2…
Two-four-six, four, two...
2   4-7…
...two, four-seven...
5-7   6-7…
...five-seven, six-seven...
7   7…
...seven, seven...
7   7   7   7   7…
...seven, seven, seven...
...seven!
Seven.
我知道了 这样如何…
Oh! I got it. How about something like:
"摩妮卡 回顾我们在一起的时间…"
"Monica, when I look back over our time together..."
- 然后呢？ - 不能全部都要我做吧
- Yeah?     - I can't do all of it.
回顾你们在一起的时间
Look back over your time together.
看 双胞胎
Oh, look, twins!
不公平 我连一个都没有 为什么他们有两个？
No fair! I don't even have one, how come they get two?
- 你会有一个的   - 是啊 什么时候？
- You'll get one.     - Yeah, when?
这样吧
All right, I'll tell you what.
等40岁的时候 如果我们都还没结婚…
When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
- 我们俩来生一个如何？ - 我为什么会40岁还没结婚？
- ...what do you say we have one?     - Why wouldn't I be married?
不 不 我只是说"假设"
Oh, no, no, no. I just meant hypothetically.
好 我们来假设 我为什么会40岁还没结婚？
Hypothetically, why won't I be married?
不 不
No, no.
怎么了？真的 我是有什么 基本上不能结婚的地方吗？
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
- 额…   - 怎么样？
- Uh... Uh...     - Well?
我的老天  这个降落伞是一个背包
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack!
今天我要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
他知道我在这儿吗？
Think he knew I was here?
算你尽力了
Nice try.
等一下 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
- 摩妮卡…   - 啊
- Look, Monica...     - Ah!
- 没有用的   - 我保证这有用
- This is not gonna work.     - I bet this'll work.
你真棒 我爱你
You are so great! I love you.
什么？
What?
没事 我说 你真棒 然后就没说话了
I said you're so great, and then I stopped talking.
- 你说你爱我 我不敢相信   - 不 我没有
- You said you love me!     - No, I didn't.
- 有 你有   - 没有 我没有
- Yes, you did.     - No, I didn't!
- 你爱我    - 不 我不爱
- You love me!     - No, I don't!
停 停
Stop it! Stop it!
我在想 如果我在这里 打开行李呢？
You know, I was thinking, what if I, uh, unpack here?
你的东西都会在这里
Then all your stuff would be here.
那…
Well...
如果我的东西都在这里呢？
What if it was here?
那你会一直来回跑来跑去
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time.
干嘛要这样
Doesn't make any sense.
好
Okay.
如果我们住在一起 而你了解我在说什么？
What if we live together, and you understand what I'm saying?
你希望这是一个惊喜
We wanted to surprise you.
我的天
Oh, my God!
钱德…
Chandler...
我这一生…
...in all my life...
从没想过我会这么幸运…
...I never thought I'd be so lucky...
能爱上我最好的…
...as to fall in love with my best...
我最好的… 女生不这么做是有原因的
My best... There's a reason why girls don't do this!
好 好 我来
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
我以为…
I thought...
我做得到
I can do this.
我以为…
I thought...
我说什么 和在哪里说很重要
...that it mattered what I said or where I said it.
但我发现唯一重要的是你…
Then I realized the only thing that matters is that you...
你让我比我能想像的更快乐
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
如果你愿意…
And if you let me...
我要用这一生 来让你有同样的成觉
...I'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
摩妮卡？
Monica?
嫁给我好吗？
Will you marry me?
好
Yes.
我们可以进来了吗？ 我们快要死了
Can we come in? We're dying out here!
进来 进来
Come in! Come in!
- 我们订婚了    - 好啊
- We're engaged!     - Yes!
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
- 嗨   - 你们在干嘛？
- Hi.      - What have you guys been up to?
帮忙钱德写他的婚礼誓词 但被他踢出来了…
Uh, helping Chandler write his vows. He kicked us out.
因为乔伊一直提出 不得体的建议
Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions.
"摩妮卡 我爱你的美臀" 有什么不得体的地方？
How is "Monica, I love your sweet ass" inappropriate?
摩妮卡写得怎么样？
How's Monica doing?
这样说吧 幸好她有一个美臀 因为她不太擅长写作
Lucky she's got a sweet ass. She's not so good at writing.
真不敢相信再4个星期 他们就要结婚了
In four weeks they're gonna be married!
希望他们能白头到老
Let's just hope it works.
10个里面有9个以离婚收场
Nine out of 10 marriages end in divorce.
菲比 没有的事
Heh. That's not true.
是啊 你说的对 你太太好吗？
You're right. How's the missus?
真不敢相信…
I can't believe...
- 他们在一起3年了   - 那么久了？
- ...they're together 3 years.     - That long?
感觉没那么久 因为他们瞒了我们很久
It seems like less because they hid it from us.
是我 进来了
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
我今天辛苦了一整天
I've had a very long, hard day.
- 我要去买炸鸡 你要不要？ - 不 谢了 不要炸鸡 再见
- Uh, I'm getting chicken. Want some?     - Uh, no. Bye, then.
你还好吧？抱歉
Are you okay? I'm so sorry.
他不肯离开 一直问要不要炸鸡
He wouldn't leave. He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
炸鸡？
Chicken?
我可以来点炸鸡
I could eat some chicken.
乔伊
Hey, Joe!
我想要三块鸡肉 包心菜沙拉 豆子 还有可乐
Can I get a, uh, three-piece, uh, coleslaw, beans and a Coke?
健怡可乐
Diet Coke.
- 不知道他们为什么不直接告诉我们   - 对啊 好像我们不会认同似的
- Why didn't they tell us?      - I know, we were cool about it.
你？和你？
You? And you?
对 但你不能说 没有人知道
You cannot tell. No one knows.
怎么会？什么时候？
How? When?
- 在伦敦发生的   - 在伦敦
- It happened in London.     - In London?
我们没告诉任何人 因为我们不希望小事变大
We didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
可是这是大事
But it is a big deal!
- 我一定要告诉人   - 不 不要
- I have to tell someone.     - No, no!
- 不可以   - 拜托拜托
- You can't.     - Please!
我们不想面对告诉大家之后的事 答应我你不会说
We don't want to deal with telling them. Just promise you won't tell.
好啦
All right!
等不及要和你在一起
I can't wait to be with you.
我去告诉瑞秋 我要洗几个小时的衣服
I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry.
洗衣服？那是我的新昵称吗？
Laundry, huh? Is that my new nickname?
啊
Aw.
你知道你的昵称是什么 大…
You know your nickname, Mr. Big...
看 是摩妮卡和钱德 嘿 嘿 你们两个 嘿
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler. Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
钱德和摩妮卡
Chandler and Monica!
我的天
Oh, my God!
- 钱德和摩妮卡    - 我的天
- Aah! Chandler and Monica!     - Oh, my God!
- 我的眼睛 我的眼睛    - 菲比 菲比
- Oh, my eyes! My eyes!     - Phoebe! Phoebe!
- 没事的 没事的    - 不 他们在亲热
- It's okay! It's okay!      - No! They're doing it!
我知道 我知道
I know! I know!
- 你知道？ - 对 我知道
- You know?     - Yes!
乔伊也知道 但罗斯不知道  你不要再尖叫了
And Joey, but Ross doesn't, so stop screaming!
嗨 怎么了啊？
Hey, what's going on?
什么？怎么了？
What? What?
老天 我们好兴奋 你可能会搬来这儿
We're excited that you might get this place!
- 事实上 这里看起来很不错   - 看来很不错
- Actually, it looks really good.      - It looks pretty good!
过来这里 来
Get in here! Come on!
现在他们知道你知道 但他们不知道瑞秋知道？
So they don't know that Rachel knows?
对 但你知道吗？ 谁知道什么并不重要
Yes, but it doesn't matter who knows what.
现在有足够的人知道 就可以告诉他们我们知道了
Enough of us know. We can just tell them we know.
谎言 秘密终于可以结束了
The lying and the secrets will be over.
或者我们不要告诉他们我们知道 我们就可以找点小乐子
Or, we can not tell them we know and have a little fun of our own.
好 如果想赶上电影的话 我们该走了
We better go if we're gonna catch that movie.
- 再见   - 再见
- Bye.      - Bye.
再见 钱德 我已经开始想你了
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
你看到了吗？ 她很不得体地捏我一把？
Did you see the inappropriate pinching?
我看到了
Actually, I did.
你现在相信她喜欢上我了吧？
So now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
我的天  我的天 她知道我们的事
Oh, my God! My God, she knows about us!
- 菲比知道我们的事    - 我没有告诉她们
- Phoebe knows about us!     - I didn't tell them.
她们？她们是谁？
Them? Who's them?
菲比和乔伊
Uh, Phoebe and Joey.
乔伊
Joey!
还有瑞秋
And Rachel.
我本来要告诉你们的 可是她们要我保证不说
They made me promise not to tell.
她们以为她们很厉害 这样耍我们
They think they are so slick, messing with us!
可是 她们不知道 我们知道她们知道
They don't know that we know that they know.
- 所以   - 对
- So...     - Ah, yes!
耍人的变成被耍的
The messers become the messees!
我的天 他要我过去摸他的二头肌还有别的
My God, he wants me to come over and feel his biceps!
- 你开玩笑吧？ - 不
- Are you kidding?     - No.
我不相信 他会对摩妮卡这样…
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo...
乔伊？他们知道我们知道了吗？
Joey? Do they know that we know?
- 不知道   - 乔伊
- No.     - Joey!
- 他们知道你们知道   - 我就知道
- They know you know.      - Ugh! I knew it!
不能相信这两个人
I cannot believe those two!
他们以为可以耍我们？ 他们想要耍我们？
They thought that they could mess with us? With us?
他们不知道我们知道他们知道我们知道了
They don't know that we know they know we know.
乔伊 你什么也不能说
Joey, you can't say anything.
就算我想说 也不知道要怎么说
Couldn't if I wanted to.
这完全失控了
This is totally getting out of hand.
- 她要我替她抹乳液    - 她在唬你
- She wants me to put lotion on her!     - She's bluffing!
她没有退缩 她还这样…
She's not backing down. She went like this.
他没有退缩 他去拿乳液了
He's not backing down. He went to get lotion.
天啊 你们还没玩完吗？
Oh, man. Aren't you guys done yet?
乔伊 菲比早点攻破钱德 这事就会早一点公开
The sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler the sooner this is all over.
- 我喜欢   - 好
- Ooh, I like that.     - Okay.
对了 给他看你的胸罩 他最怕胸罩了 他不会解胸罩
Okay, show him your bra. He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
哇 你没拉掉任何扣子
Wow! You didn't rip off any buttons.
也不是第一次
It's not my first time.
回去外面 勾引她直到解决掉她
You go seduce her until she cracks.
好 给我一秒钟
Okay, give me a second.
- 你清洗了这儿？   - 当然
- Did you clean up in here?     - Of course.
你要走了？
Oh, you're, uh, going?
除非你一起来 爱人
Um, not without you, lover.
这是我的胸罩
So, this is my bra.
非常非常的好看
It's very, very nice.
过来
Well, come here.
我非常开心我们要上床了
I'm happy we're gonna have all the sex.
你应该开心的 我的柔软度很好
You should be. Heh. I'm very bendy.
- 我现在要吻你了   - 如果我没先吻你的话
- I'm gonna kiss you.     - Not if I kiss you first.
我想我们除了接吻 没有别的事可做了
There's nothing left for us to do but kiss.
来了
Here it comes.
我们的初吻
Our first kiss.
- 好 好 好 好 你赢了   -  哈
- Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win!     - Ha!
- 我不能和你上床   - 为什么不能？
- I can't have sex.     - Why not?
- 因为我爱摩妮卡    - 你什么？
- I'm in love with Monica.      - You're what?
爱她 对 我爱她 我爱她
Love her! That's right, I love her! I love her!
我爱你 摩妮卡
I love you, Monica.
我也爱你  钱德
I love you too, Chandler.
我以为你们两个只是上床 我不知道你们恋爱了
I thought you guys were doing it, I didn't know you were in love.
就是这样 结束了 大家都知道了
That's it, it's over. Everybody knows.
- 其实 罗斯还不知道    - 请大家还不要告诉他
- Well, Ross doesn't.      - We'd like it if no one told him yet.
不
No.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
放开我妹
Get off my sister!
朋友要结婚了 很多事会改变的
Friends getting married, it's gotta change things.
你觉得真的会不一样吗？
Think it'll be different?
怎么能不变呢？ 他们很快就会有小孩…
How can it not be? They're gonna have kids...
会和其他有孩子的夫妇在一起
...and hang out with other couples who have kids.
也许他们会搬离城市…
And maybe they'll leave the city...
到某个靠近富豪车商的地方
...to be near a Volvo dealership.
事情会变的
Things change.
我不要他们搬到 卖富豪车的地方
I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership.
乔伊 不会怎么样的
It'll be okay, Joe. Heh.
抱歉 我只是… 我希望能像以前一样
Sorry. I just... I like things the way they are.
这个光着身子的小孩是谁？
Who's this little naked guy?
这个光着身子的小孩是我
Uh, that naked guy would be me.
- 你看这小东西   - 哈哈
- Ha, aw, look at the little thing.      - Ha-ha-ha.
是啊
Yes.
是的 好 那是我的小鸡鸡 我们现在可以做大人了吗？
Yes, fine, that is my penis. Can we be grownups now?
- 这些是谁？   - 该我了
- Who are those people?     - Got me.
那中间的是奶奶
Oh, that's Nana right there.
- 哇哦   - 我看看
- Wow.     - Let's see.
"我和爪哇咖啡店里的那一群"
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
摩妮卡 你长得很像你祖母 那时她几岁？
Wow. Monica, you look like your grandma. How old was she?
我看看 1939
Let's see, 1939.
对 24 25岁
Yeah, uh, 24, 25.
看起来很快乐的一群
Huh. Looks like a fun gang.
看 看 看  我找到摩妮卡光着身子的
Ooh! Look, look, look! I got Monica naked.
我看
Let me see.
不 这还是我
No, that would be me again.
嘿 大伙儿
Hey, you guys.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
- 你们在做什么？ - 我们刚刚提到…
- What's going on?     - Well, we were just talking about...
你们要结婚了 是大喜事
...you guys getting married and how great it is.
对 如果你们真的想要 可以买一台富豪
Yeah, you can get a Volvo. If that's what you really want.
- 你们真好   - 哈
- That's so sweet.     - Hmm.
- 我们都写完婚礼誓词了   - 我们可以看吗？
- So, we both finished our vows.     - Can we read them?
只要我没听到钱德的 他没听到我的就好
As long as I don't hear his and he doesn't hear mine.
- 好   - 好
- Okay.     - Okay.
- 啊    - 哦
- Aw.     - Oh.
好美哦
Oh, that's beautiful.
好好笑 很好
Funny one! Good!
摩妮卡 你嫁给我好吗？
Will you marry me?
- 哈哈哈   - 什么？我不懂
- Ha-ha-ha.     - What? I don't get it.
是哟
Oh, yeah!
- 这太爆笑了   - 钱德
- Man, this is hilarious!     - Chandler!
甜心 别担心 我们会让你的好笑一点
Don't worry, we'll make yours funnier.
你们觉得如何？
Okay, what do you think?
- 老兄   - 我从没见过这样的爱
- Dude...     - I have never known love like this.
- 你真的喜欢？ - 老兄
- You really like it?     - Dude!
你怎么写出来的？
How did you write this?
我偷了摩妮卡的 然后改掉名字
I stole Monica's and changed the name. Shh.
- 你不能这么做   - 如果他先讲的话就可以
- You can't do that!     - If he goes first he can!